A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3 FA137
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject files, 1902-1965; 3
  - Materials from the Business Manager's office, 1902-1965; 1.8 Cubic Feet; 34 boxes
    - Radium, 1907-1925 1925-1959 (Box 28)
      From original purchase and development of equipment to disposal.
      Includes 1933 correspondence of Ralph W.G. Wyckoff and S. Flexner regarding uses of Institute radium. Agreement with Memorial Hospital regarding loan of radium.
    - Real estate, 1915-1957 (Box 28)
      Includes early offers to sell to Institute land area between 63rd and 64th and Avenue A and East River bulkhead.
    - Regional Plan Association, 1922-1936 (Box 28)
    - Reference letters (employees), 1926-1948 (Box 28)
    - Relief, 1946-1947 (Box 28)
      CARE packages for Pasteur Institute of Athens.
    - Rest rooms (Employees), 1931-1951 (Box 28)
      See also Employees; Employees (Men's Committee).
    - Reports, 1919-1954 (Box 29)
      Primarily copies and covering letters and reminders of date due and form.
    - Residence, 1929-1962 (Box 29)
      Primarily apartments rented through O.A. Robertson, Real Estate.
      See also Dining and Residence Halls; Sophie Fricke (Fellows, Housing).
    - Rickettsia; Ringer, Adolph Irving; Robinson, G.H.; Rogers, B.C.; Rowlands, T. (Box 29)
      Applications for grants; Rowlands (employee illness).
    - Retirement plan withdrawals, 1925-1960 (Box 29)
      See also Bus. Mgr. / Counsel Correspondence.
    - Retirement plans, 1912-1932 1933-1939 1940-1956 (Box 29)
      Comparisons with other institutions; studies; calculations; copies of correspondence.
      See also Annuities; Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association.
    - Rockefeller Family, 1931-1960 (Box 29)
      Sketchy correspondence with assorted family members.
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1913-1949 (Box 30)
      Correspondence regarding funds for war related purposes; sera preparation; War Demonstration Hospital; correspondence with G. Vincent.
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Edwin R. Embree), 1917-1924 (Box 30)
      Deals primarily with grant appropriations for special projects; includes 13p. handwritten addition by S. Flexner to report on war activities; also includes authorization for disposal of War Demonstration Hospital buildings.
    - Rockefeller Foundation Comptroller, 1915-1923 (Box 30)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 30)
      Also includes early letters covering payments to RIMR by General Education Board.
      - General Education Board, 1908-1927
      - International Education Board, 1924-1927
    - Rockefeller Foundation China Medical Board, 1915-1947 (Box 30)
      Includes information on support of Peking Medical College.
    - Rockefeller Foundation International Health Board, 1912-1926 (Box 30)
      Includes 1914-1915 correspondence on purchase of Thymol used by Sanitary Commission in treatment of Hookworm. Communications in reference to workers, space needs, remodeling of space, arrangements for charges and making payments.
    - Rockefeller Foundation I.H.D., 1927-1934 1935-1942 1943-1953 (Box 31)
      Before 1927 called International Health Board which developed from Sanitary Commission for Eradication of Hookworm. Includes program for Conference on Leprosy 1950; correspondence regarding horses for serum production; also includes formalization of space arrangements. After 1952 name seems to have changed to Division of Medicine and Public Health?.
    - Ruprecht, Frank, 1919-1921 (Box 31)
      Suit against RIMR in autopsy case.
    - Rutgers College, 1915-1918 (Box 31)
      RIMR requests for advice in farm personnel and storing fruits and vegetables. Institute offer of assistance in adverse animal experimentation ruling.
    - Sa-Sv (Box 31)
      Includes material on retirement party for Florence Stewart; report of study of RIMR business methods, 1941 made by Frank S. Staley.
    - Salaries-statistics, 1903-1942 1943-1953 (Box 32)
      Correspondence, tables, memoranda on salary comparisons, stabilizations and increases.
      Includes 1911 table prepared by Abraham Flexner.
    - Social Security, 1950-1965 (Box 32)
      Details of meetings and correspondence when RIMR joined SS.
    - Social Service, 1913-1959 (Box 32)
      Includes early correspondence with Ida Cannon.
      Includes reports, 1922/1923-1935/1936.
    - Space situation, 1956 (Box 32)
    - Spectroscope Laboratory (Box 32)
    - Stokes, James B., 1929-1958 (Box 32)
    - Storrs Agricultural Station (Box 32)
    - Student affairs, 1955-1961 (Box 32)
      Includes dates and titles of lectures, 1955-1959[?].
    - Subpoenas (Box 32)
    - Storeroom, 1914-1938 (Box 33)
    - Studies, 1912-1953 (Box 33)
    - T.I.A.A., 1942-1963 (Box 33)
      (Includes CREF).
      see also Retirement plans.
    - Treuhaft, Julius, 1918 (Box 33)
      Hospital record.
      See also Subpoenas; see also Minutes of Scientific Directors.
    - Tryparsamide, 1914-1946 (Box 33)
      Includes copies of Pearce and Wade reports 1925-1926.
      Correspondence with Public Health Institute regarding their cooperation in testing; material about Trademark and license agreement for manufacture, 1925.
      see also Patents; see also Fish, Richardson, Herrick & Neave.
    - U.S. Department of Labor, 1932 (Box 33)
      Immigration admission of research students.
    - U.S. Post Office, 1909-1949 (Box 33)
    - Van Heusen (John Manning) Estate Bequest (Box 33)
    - Various: Timmons; Zervos (Box 33)
    - Wadsworth, Augustus B., 1913-1933 (Box 33)
      Includes early correspondence with Columbia University on research grant; later as Director of N.Y. State Department of Health Laboratory.
    - War relief and research, 1916-1917 (Box 33)
      Correspondence between Henry James and William T. Porter on mission to Belgium to study shock and recommend methods of treatment. Also correspondence with J.P. Simonds.
    - Waverly Press, 1915-1930 (Box 33)
      see also Press/Publications Division.
    - Various: Crank correspondence, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Patent records, circa 1913-1936; circa 2.5 cubic feet
    Primarily re tryparsamide; also includes material on arsenicals, luetin, acetone production, and intrapharyngeal apparatus. C. Kopp, 13 Nov 1985.
    - Intrapharyngeal apparatus, 1913 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Tryparsamide correspondence, circa 1919-1936 (Box 35)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1920-1922 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1923 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave 1924 I (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave 1924 II (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1925 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1926 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Fish, Richardson, and Neave, 1928 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - General, 1919-1920 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - General, 1922 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - General, 1923 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - General, 1924 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - General, 1925 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - General, 1926 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - General, 1933-1934 1936 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - General, undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - May and Becker, Ltd., 1925-1934 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Poulence Freres (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Powers-Weightman-Rosengarten. Merck and Co., 1923-1929 (Box 35, Folder 21)
      - Synthetic Drug Co. (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - A-189, 5" Letter
      - 1917 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - 1918 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - I, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - II, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - I, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - II, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - I, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - II, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - III, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - A-189, 2.5" Letter
      - I, 1922 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - II, 1922 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - 1923-1924 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Foreign patents (primarily arsenicals), 5" Legal
      - Argentina (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Australia (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Belgium I (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Belgium II (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Brazil (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Canada (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Chile (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Denmark (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - France (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Great Britain (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Holland (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Holland II (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Holland III (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Foreign patents (primarily arsenicals), 5" Legal (Box 39)
      - Holland IV (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - India (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Italy (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Japan (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Norway (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - South Africa, Union of (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Spain (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Sweden (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Switzerland (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Tryparsamide, Certificates of registration of trade-mark (foreign)
      - A-B (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - C (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - D (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - E (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - F (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - G (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - H (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - I (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - J (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - M (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - N (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - P (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - R (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - S (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - U (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Envelopes (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Arsenicals. Jacobs, Brown, Heidelberger, and Pearce (Box 40)
      - Petition and assignment, 1917 October 3 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - U.S. Patent Nos. 1,280,119 to 1,280,127, 24 Sep 1918; 1,315,127, 2 Sep 1919 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Assignment, Canada, 1918 October 7 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Tryparsamide, Certificates of filing trade-mark, circa 1922-1924 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Acetone Production (John H. Northrop). U.S. Patent 1,293,172, 1919 February 4 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Luetin re manufacture and trade-mark registration. I (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Luetin. re manufacture and trade-mark registration. II (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Luetin. re manufacture and trade-mark registration. Envelopes (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Administrative staff files, 5" letter
    The following files were found at the end of a series of folders on the scientific staff (see 450. 1), and consist of administrative staff files. They were originally stored in the Welch Hall vault on the 1st basement floor.
    - Cogger, John W., 1954-1958 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Dickey, Frank A., 1919-1920 1933 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Goepper, Herman, 1911-1920 1935 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Howe, F. Stanley, 1920-1950 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Robertson, Albert D., photos, 1930-1946 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Shotwell, Willets H., 1949 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Smillie, Ernest W., clippings, 1915-1958 (Box 41, Folder 7-10)
    - Spies, Charles B., 1914-1938 (Box 41, Folder 11-13)
      E.B. Smith notes, inventory sheets, etc.
    - Taylor, George W., 1940-1950 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Trask, Lillia M.D., 1911-1952 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Van Sise, Kenneth E., 1958-1961 (Box 41, Folder 16-17)
      Memoranda and reports 28 Aug 86: ck.
  - Personnel wages, 1959-1963; 2.5" letter
    Files previously stored at beginning of 450.1 series (see above) in Welch Hall vault.
    - Area Wage Survey, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Area Wage Survey, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Area Wage Survey (2 copies), 1961 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Wage Increases for employees (RIMR), 1962 December-1963 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Booklet: "Survey of Current Business." U.S. Department of Commerce, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Institute's "Third Section"
    Boxes 43 and 44 contain papers about the so-called "Third Section" of the Institute, ca 1909-14. This was a proposal to establish special public health activities, including a Museum of Hygiene, at RIMR. The material in these two boxes was found in two packages in the Welch Hall vault, part of the files of the Business Manager. There is very little correspondence, and the file is incomplete regarding the narrative history of the proposal: i.e. the origins, response, and outcome are poorly documented in this file.
    The major report of October 1914 was included in the "Report to the Scientific Directors," Record Group 439, Vol. 3.
    - Correspondence, 1909 1914 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts and drafts, undated (Box 43, Folder 2-21)
      Arranged in approximate chronological order (many are undated); untitled drafts/mss are at the end of this series, folders 17-21.
    - "A Third Section of The Rockefeller Institute", circa 1910 (Box 43, Folder 2-3)
    - "Suggestions for a Report to the Trustees of The Rockefeller Institute by the Scientific Directors on the Establishment of New Activities for the Promotion of the Public Health". ca 1913. Various copies, some annotated, circa 1913 (Box 43, Folder 4-7)
    - "Revised. Suggestions for a Report...", circa 1914 (Box 43, Folder 8-9)
    - "A Report to the Trustees of The Rockefeller Institute by the Scientific Directors on the Establishment of New Activities for the Promotion of the Public Health. October 17, 1914". Various copies, few annotations, 1914 October 17 (Box 43, Folder 10-13)
    - "Summary Accompanying the Report on the Establishment of New Activities for the Promotion of the Public Health. October 17, 1914", 1914 October 17 (Box 43, Folder 14-15)
      Various copies, few annotations.
    - Councilman, W.T. "A Projected Museum of Hygiene." Comments on "Third Section", undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Untitled manuscripts and drafts (Box 43, Folder 17-21)
      Includes excerpt (folder 20) re use of moving pictures.
    - Estimates, 2.5" letter (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - untitled, Holograph and typescript outlines with queries and ideas [Henry James?] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Printed material (Box 44, Folder 4-8)
      Includes booklets on the Deutsches Museum (Munich) and Pathoplastiaches Institut (Dresden).
  - History of Retirement Allowance Plan for [RIMR] Scientific Staff adopted July 1924, 1924 July; 10 folders, 5" letter. GL 10/86
    From the Business Manager's Files. [Information from original package label].
    - Proposed Plan of Retirement and Insurance for the Rockefeller Foundation, 1923 May 17 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Pamphlet includes 18 pp carbon copy of Retirement Plan, 1 page Index and 1 page Tables index.
    - Proposed Plan for Retiring Allowances, Group Insurance, and Individual Insurance. [For Rockefeller Foundation], 1923 May 22 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Duplicated copy. Includes index and 8 pp of Proposed Plan. Also includes handwritten notes by [Business Manager?] dated Aug 29, 1923 re RIMR Retiring Allowances and Insurance.
    - Report of Committee on Retiring Allowances for RIMR, 1923 October 19 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Working copy. Also includes handwritten notes re other institutions.
    - Preliminary Study of Groups to be Considered in Plan for Retiring Allowances [RIMR], 1924 February 7 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - [Actuarial Report]. Memorandum Setting Forth the Amount of the Estimated Benefits Payable by the RIMR on account of Certain Members and Associate Members under the Rules Governing Retiring Allowances, 1924 March 8 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Includes carbon copy of letter from George B. Buck, Consulting Actuary/ E.B. Smith, re a supplement to report of March 8.
    - Notes on Retiring Allowances and Group Insurance Plan, 1924 April 22 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Includes handwritten and typescript drafts of Notes on... by Simon Flexner dated Apr 21, 1924 included w/Apr 22 notes. Also handwritten memos from Simon Flexner/E.B. Smith re notes.
    - Report of Committee on Retiring Allowances for RIMR, 1924 May 14 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Presented at meeting of RIMR Board of Trustees held on May 1, 1924. Includes 1924 May 29, Raymond B. Fosdick, Secretary/E.B. Smith, re approval of report.
    - Revisions by Mr. Fosdick, Dr. Flexner and E.B. Smith for Plan for Retiring Allowances adopted by Board of Trustees May 14, 1924, 1924 June 5 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Includes various duplicated copies of Plan and Revisions.
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.A. (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Exchange between E.B. Smith/Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U.S.A. re Group Insurance, 1923 July 17-23 1923 October 22
        Includes printed material by Equitable and some handwritten notes.
    - Rockefeller Foundation material re retirement plan and insurance, 1923-1924 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      Includes material re Peking Union Medical College (PUMC), RF, International Health Board of RF.
    - Miscellaneous printed material re annuities, insurance and compensation (Box 45, Folder 10)
      Includes:.
      - Carnegie Institution of Washington. Plans for annuities and insurance, 1919 April
      - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Assoc of America (TIAA), 1928
      - U.S. Bureau of Efficiency, 1920
    - Preliminary material leading up to Retiring Allowance Plan adopted for Scientific Staff [RIMR], 1924 July 1; 10 folders
      Business Manager's Office. Most of material taken out to show Mr. Smith Feb 24, 1930. Initialed H.D.?. [Information from original package label] Material reviewed by Mr. W.R. Flinn in January 1958. [On original envelope].
      - Carnegie Foundation. Original Plan of Retiring Allowances, 1906 April 9 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Some Early work of Dr. Prudden's on pensions (Box 45, Folder 12)
        [Pencilled note. Plan of TMP [T. Mitchell Prudden] turned down. 3/4 adopted.].
        Includes: A Proposed System of Pensions for Employees other than Members of the Scientific Staff. [Pencilled note. Not adopted]. ca 1911.
      - Handwritten notes re expenses for maintenance of doctors, nurses and other staff at RIMR Hospital, circa 1922? (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Handwritten notes re setting up Pension Plan (Box 45, Folder 14)
        Includes notes re other institutions.
      - Miscellaneous material re retiring allowances and insurance, 1923-1924 (Box 45, Folder 15)
        Includes News clippings and 1923 Lists of Members of RIMR Corporation. Includes Board of Trustees, Board of Sci Dirs and Executive Officers and 1923-1924 Scientific and Administrative Staff, TIAA printed material and notes, 1923 Nov Disability, insurance and pensions [RIMR], 1923 Dec 12, Memo to E.B. Smith re Total Personnel of Institute.
        - News clippings: New York Times, "Life Insurance Thriving", 1923 October 29
        - News clippings: The World, "Hays Pension Plan for Clergy Wins", 1924 May 26
        - Interview w/Dr. Flexner, 1924 February 4
          Handwritten notes attached to, "Notes on Retiring Allowances and Group Insurance" by Simon Flexner.
        - [RIMR] Scientific Staff, 1924 February 11
          Lists of members and associate members giving date of birth, present age, marital status, present salary. Carbon copy.
        - George E. Buck, Consulting Actuary/ E.B. Smith re copies of a memorandum (report) giving an estimate of the liabilities of the Institute under the "Rules Covering the Retiring Allowances", 1924 March 8-11
          Includes copies of report and supplement w/ S.F. (Simon Flexner) memo to E.B. Smith and other notes attached.
        - "Revised Study of Groups to be Considered in Plan for Retiring Allowances." w/handwritten notes by S.F. and suggestions by T.M. Prudden attached to 1924 Feb, "Preliminary Study...", 1924 March 15
        - Handwritten notes on talk w/Mr. Kirs on Retiring Allowances, 1924 April 9
        - Lists of names. Special Group
          Handwritten.
        - [RIMR] Employees over 30 w/at least 1 year of service w/working material, 1924 May 2
        - Scientific Staff Appointments, Promotions and Salaries to take effect July 1, 1924, 1924 July 1
      - re Extension of Retiring Allowance Plan adopted by Board of Trustees on June 16, 1924 to Certain Members of Institute and to a Selected Group of Employees as of Jan 1, 1925 w/handwritten figures to July 1, 1925 (Box 45, Folder 16)
        Includes handwritten notes, figures and working materials.
      - Board of Trustees meeting. Docket of business of, 1927 May 16 (Box 45, Folder 17)
        Includes material on pension and retirement plans. Also includes 1924 exchange (handwritten) between S. Flexner/ E.B. Smith w/ working materials and handwritten notes by E.B. Smith on Report of Committee on Retiring Allowances, 1924 Board of Trustees meeting.
      - Waldo R. Flinn/D. Whitaker re arrangement for Editha C. Campbell retiring allowance, 1958 January 17 (Box 45, Folder 18)
        Includes 1924 June, RIMR Plan for Retiring Allowances w/1951 June 11 Amendment to Clause A, adopted by [RIMR] Board of Trustees. Typescript of.
      - Forecast of cost of retiring plan to selected group of RIMR employees, 1924 January 16 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Brief on Retirement Plan for Rockefeller Foundation [RF] and Subsidiary Boards. Submitted by Raymond B. Fosdick, 1921 (Box 45, Folder 20)
        Includes material re RI Plan. 35 pp typescript, 1922 Apr 25, George B. Buck "Memorandum Regarding the Type of Retirement System to be Adopted for Employees of the RF and Subsidiary Boards and the RIMR, the General Education Board and the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial" to Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Recommendations of Committee on Retiring Allowance for the R.I.M.R. adopted at Meeting of the Board of Trustees held May 14, 1924, revised June 5, 1924, 6 folders, 5" letter. 10/86 GL
    From the Business Manager's Office file. [From original envelope label].
    - re Retiring Allowances for RIMR, 1924 May-June (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Retiring Allowance Data, 1924 July; 2 folders
      History Cards Used in Computing date for Plan Adopted July 1924. [From original label on envelope].
      - Hand numbered #1-#179 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Hand numbered #180-#367 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Pension records. Office of Business Manager. Salary cards, 2 folders
      - Salary cards (1), 1924 February 7 (Box 46, Folder 4)
        Includes: Preliminary study of groups to be considered in plan for retiring allowances. Various titles/groups separated w/bond paper.
      - Salary cards (2) (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Pensions - Other than scientific (Box 46, Folder 6)
      [From original envelope].
      Includes printed material from other intuitions and accident plans, 1913 news clipping, N.Y. Times, "10,000,000. Pension Plan in Operation." re AT&T. Also includes: A Proposed System of Pensions for Employees other than Members of the Scientific Staff to take effect, January 1, 1912 and various listings of staff other than scientific, w/salary and pension information.
  - Pensions Scientific [Staff], 5 folders, 5" letter. GL 10/86
    - Dr. Prudden-Pensions (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence w/Henry James and Dr. Prudden
      - Drafts of Pension Plan at various stages
      - "Rules Governing Retiring Allowances for Members and Associate Members of the Staff of the RIMR", 1913 May 22
        Printed copies.
    - re Pensions Systems and other institutions, 1913 February-November 28 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence w/ Clyde Furst, Carnegie Foundation w/attachment of letter re University of Chicago pension system.
      R.S. Woodward/Henry James re RI pension scheme.
      F.P. Mall/Simon Flexner re RIMR rules for retiring allowances for members.
      Bus Mgr? /E. Roux, Director of Pasteur Institute re RIMR pension scheme.
      Nicholas Murray Butler/Henry James re Columbia University retirement plan.
      Printed material and typescripts (carbon copies) re retirement plans at other institutions.
    - Files maintained by Henry James/Jerome D. Greene, 3 folders